WenCheng Lin

Phone: +1(443) 280-9976 wenchenglin29@gmail.com

Mailing Address Oakland, CA 4615-9997

A passionate full stack developer with extensive experience in all the phase of frontend and backend development. Through my career as a full stack developer I have focused on developing scalable and well documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with projects on my own. Excited about the prospect of joining product-driven companies.

EDUCATION

MS National University Singapore

June 2015 Thesis: "Computer Science"

Advisor: Jessuis

EXPERIENCES AND SKILLS

- -6 years of full stack development including planning, requirement analysis, design, development, testing.
- -6 years of backend development in Node.js and Python
- -6 years of frontend development using JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, Vue.js, VueX,

Hard Skills:

- -Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python
- -Frameworks: React.js, Vue.js, Node.js, Django
- -Database: MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Oracle
- -Cloud Service: Google Cloud Console, AWS/Lambda, Heroku
- -Project management Tool: Jira, Github/Gitlab

Soft Skills:

- -Excellent interpersonal and Communication Skills
- -Optimistic and Honest Attitue
- -Passion for Learning and Challenging New Skills

LANGUAGE AND COMMUNICATION TOOLS

Language: English

Communication Tools: Phone, Email, Skype, Telegram, Discord, Whatsapp.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

NutriSense(San Francisco, US)

Jul 2020 - May 2022

- About the Client

NutriSense is a platform focused on improving metabolic health. Our mission is to help anybody discover and reach their health potential. Our members discover the perfect diet for their unique bodies by tracking key metabolic markers in real-time. We leverage powerful hardware (CGM, Ketone Meters, etc), software, and a team of expert dietitians to enable lasting behavior change. We provide the tools and support our members need to make smarter food and lifestyle decisions.

-Project Name: TechSpecs Role: Full Stack developer Team members: 2 members Communication: Slack

Tech Stack: Next.js, React.js, Redux, -Saga, React Hooks, Node.js

Dragos(Houston, United Kingdom)

Apr 2018 - Jun 2020

-About the client

Dragos was founded by renowned ICS/OT practitioners who have defeated adversaries for the U.S. government, ally nations, and global firms. Today, Dragos is on a mission to protect the world's most critical infrastructure and safeguard civilization. We know that's a mission you can get behind.

-Project Name: Arootah

Role: Backend developer Team members: 3 members Communication: Slack, Discord Tech Stack: Node.js, Typescript

Goals & Objectives

- -Created an app for the travel industry
- -Created a marketplace for the travel industry similar to Fiverr
- -Created an app where buyers(tourists) can obtain information and travel related services from sellers.
- -Created a typical e-commerce based system for generating revenue(percentage from each transactions)

Features

- -User Role management(buyer, seller)
- -Message Feature(Chatting APP).
- -Payment integration(Stripe)
- -Email, SMS Verfication(Twillio)
- -Upload Video/Image to AWS
- -Streaming Video

ChatHop(New York, US)

Aug 2016 – Mar 2018

React.js/Node.js Integration

- Safety365 is a Saas Platform aimaing to save lives of people with coding, providing compliance scores for all the possible risk handing options and risk assessment, and serves big clients like Coca-Cola(EU)
- Revamped the whole SaaS platform based on React.js and restructured the backend separating it from the front end in Laravel to optimize the load speed
- Led a team of 4 remote developers for the integration of all the assets and played a role of QA Engineer for the COSSH Assessment